

Resume of

MAHARUL ALAM RASEL

Address: House No - C-1/10 (Deshari), Bangladesh Rice Research Institute R/A,

Gazipur – 1701, Bangladesh Mobile No : +8801843311445 E-mail: maharulalam@gmail.com

Career Objective:

Seeking to assume demanding leadership assignments relationship management with the buyer & buying house. I always value competency, dynamism, hard work and achievement. My sense of Satisfaction in defined primarily through success and accomplishments.

Career Summary:

My background includes successfully developing and implementing strategic merchandise plans, establishing solid relationships with vendors, and facilitating product awareness efforts to maximize profit enhancement and product turnover. Through my experience, I have achieved success in driving consistent sales and gross margin increases. Additionally, my established ability to schedule and manage staff positions me to make a significant contribution to your company.

Special Qualification:

Pricing and cost negotiation
Strong communication skills
Vendor management
Leadership
File and account maintenance
Project management
Quality assurance
Detail-oriented

Experience

<u>Ian 2021 - Continue</u>

Assistant General Manager (Marketing & Merchandising) LEBAZ SWEATER Ind LTD.

I am in-charge of our Merchandising department. We are making all kinds of **sweater** wear for MENS and LADIES item of our customer MAX, LIFESTYLE, RK, M-London, Zabra, Minoti etc.

Job Responsibility: -

Analyzed the market trends and buyer requirement and developed creative and innovative sample that differentiate our client's product in the marketplace. Garment costing, corresponding & dealing with buyer from inquiry to shipment Once order is confirmed, Sourcing of yarn, fabric, accessories (price negotiation)-Local and overseas within the limits of Budget.

Sourcing new buyers, negotiating orders i.e. volume/ projections/technical details/ Compliance requirements/ plant capacity/ lead-time etc.

Making the T&A, monitoring actual realization/application of the T&A weather is maintaining by the related parties like.

Helping team in resolving issues with buyers and suppliers and ensuring smooth order follow up with on time delivery.

Tracks development and production related merchandising issues. Follow up of trims & fabric deliveries to make sure in house on time with good quality and quantities.

Work closely with production units and making sure that all details regarding changes in styling, fabrics and trims as required by the buyer are recorded and implemented during order execution

<u>Iuly 18, 2016 - Dec 2020</u>

Manager Merchandising TRITON TEXTILE - BANGLADESH

I am worked in Triton Textile as a Manager Merchandising. I am worked on our sweater & Knit department for PIMKIE, ORSAY, and BIOWORLD customer. We are making all kinds of **sweater & knit wear** for MENS & LADIES.

Iob Responsibility: -

Responsibilities include coordinating the placement of order, execution, follow-up and tracking of orders and ensure quality and on-time delivery. Suggest alternatives and work proactively in order to reach best price, quality & lead-time.

Work together with Product Developer, R&D, PT, QA and sourcing team. Send the development/quotation to best suitable suppliers.

Use price history list, planned production units, capacity plan as tools when distributing quotations to suppliers.

Get back the quotation from the suppliers and analyze the price accordingly to use internal price method, quality and lead-time.

01-2012 - 07-2016

Manager Marketing & Merchandiser Zahintex Industries Ltd

I am worked in Zahintex Industries Ltd as a Manager Marketing & Merchandiser. I am in-charge of our Merchandising department. We are making all kinds of **sweater wear** for MENS, LADIES and KIDS item of our customer like Wal-Mart, Terranova, New Look, ALDI and OBS etc.

Iob Responsibility: -

Garment costing, corresponding & dealing with buyer from inquiry to shipment Once order is confirmed, Sourcing of yarn, fabric, accessories (price negotiation)-Local and overseas within the limits of Budget.

Making the T&A, monitoring actual realization/application of the T&A weather is maintaining by the related parties like.

Tracks development and production related merchandising issues. Follow up of trims & fabric deliveries to make sure in house on time with good quality and quantities.

Work closely with production units and making sure that all details regarding changes in styling, fabrics and trims as required by the buyer are recorded and implemented during order execution

<u>01-2008 - 12-2012</u>

I am worked in Dr. Rehfeld Fashion AG Germany as a Senior Merchandiser. I am looked of our **sweater** department of our NEW YORKER & TAKKO, BROADWAY & BEST BUY customer. We are making all kinds of sweater & knit wear for MENS & LADIES of our customer.

Iob Responsibility: -

Source reliable and trusted supplier for various styles Production. Do costing of various styles, negotiation price effectively & placing order.

Sourcing /developing right factory for right product in line with company compliance requirement as well as price level. Upgrade compliance standard of the factory involving compliance team.

<u>04-2005 - 12-2007</u>

Merchandiser

COMPLICES Sport & Jeans - FRANCE

I am worked in COMPLICES as a Merchandiser. I am done worked in our merchandising department. I am assisting to our senior merchandiser & our country manager. We are made all kinds of **sweater** wear for own brand & also for other customer.

Iob Responsibility: -

Source new factory for develop new range of buyer.

Production planning to meet given shipping deadlines (Time & Action Plan) Weekly visit to the supplier to review production status & all samples approval is in place. Work together with Buyers Design and Technical departments to review new products and product submissions of ordered product to ensure product integrity, quality and value.

Responsible for obtaining salesmen samples, negotiating and setting prices, deliveries and quality requirements with vendors as per customer required.

Education

05-1998 to 07-2000

National University of Bangladesh

- * Master of Commerce
- * Accounting
- * Second Class

1995 to 1997

National University of Bangladesh

- * Bachelor of commerce
- * Accounting
- * Second Class

1992 to 1994

Kazi Azim Uddin collage of Gazipur, Bangladesh

- * Higher Secondary Certificate
- * Commerce
- * First Division

1982 to 1992

Shaid Smrity High School of Gazipur, Bangladesh

- * Secondary School Certificate
- * Commerce
- * First Division

Language Proficiency:

Language	Reading	Writing	Speaking
English	High	High	High
Bangle	High	High	High
Hindi	Low	Low	Medium

Training Summary:

Training Title	Topic	Institute	Country	Location	Year	Duration
GARMENTS/BUYING MANAGEMENT & MERCHANDISING	THE MAIN OBJECTIVES OF THIS PROGRAM WEAR: A. To Develop relationship with buyer. B. Acquiring knowledge about production planning and sample development. C. To build up relationship with suppliers and order placement for materials. D. Product pricing. E. Promotion of company products.	BANGLADESH FASHION INSTITUTE (B.F.I)	Bangladesh	Dhaka	2000	6 month

Specialization

for fabrics, yarn and trim (as per buyer specifications), timely execution of production activities to meet deadlines and achieve	Fields of Specialization	Description
 Responsible from fabric, yarn development to order confirmation stage. Product development as per buyer requirements. Identify client requirements and specification, obtaining approfor proto sample, versed with technical information as regards to fabric/yarn construction as well as knowledge of cost calculation price negotiation from buyer. Sourcing Communication Responsible for capacity blocking for order well in advance in ordination with planning dept. Management skills with the customer/buyer developing product - pricing strategies for successful launch of the new design range. Coordination with the designer and design team, cost and time analysis as different stages of garment development which const the price factor of the product. Working as a team leader, inspiring the team member and activating time and action plan, timely renewal of plan. Heading technical department & responsible to give technical approval to supplier before starting production. Manage diverse activities like quality control in sampling, sour 	 Merchandising Production Marketing Pricing Sourcing 	 Following up with cross-functional departments for placing order for fabrics, yarn and trim (as per buyer specifications), timely execution of production activities to meet deadlines and achieve seamless delivery of the order to foreign buyer. Responsible from fabric, yarn development to order confirmation stage. Product development as per buyer requirements. Identify client requirements and specification, obtaining approval for proto sample, versed with technical information as regards the fabric/yarn construction as well as knowledge of cost calculation & price negotiation from buyer. Responsible for capacity blocking for order well in advance in coordination with planning dept. Management skills with the customer/buyer developing product – pricing strategies for successful launch of the new design range. Coordination with the designer and design team, cost and time analysis as different stages of garment development which constitute the price factor of the product. Working as a team leader, inspiring the team member and activating time and action plan, timely renewal of plan. Heading technical department & responsible to give technical approval to supplier before starting production. Manage diverse activities like quality control in sampling, sourcing of fabric/yarn and accessories and correct sample sizing coordination.

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Late Md. Nurul Alam Mother's Name : Mrs. Morshada Bagom

Date of Birth : March 1, 1976

Gender : Male **Marital Status** : Married Nationality : Bangladeshi Religion : Islam (Sunni)

C/O: Md. Abul Kalam Azad Masum House No: 38/1, Tinshorok, Beside of LION FEED factory. Vill: - Laksmipura Dist: - Gazipur – 1701 **Permanent Address**

Current Location : Gazipur

Reference:

Name : Md. Mobinul Hasan Organization : Unicorn Sweaters Ltd

Designation : Director

Unicorn Sweaters Ltd. Gorat, Navana Address

· Village, Ashulia, Dhaka.

Phone (Off.) : 7789893-4

Mobile : +8801799304169

E-Mail : mobin@unicornsweater.com

Relation : Professional